Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine and today we've got a great informative lesson for you.
我是Katherine，今天我们为大家准备了一堂很有教育意义的课。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to talk about an emergency situation.
我们要讨论一个紧急情况。
So what do you do when you have an emergency?
那么，遇到紧急情况时你会怎么做？
You dial 911.
你会拨打911。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright, well maybe not in your country but today we're talking about emergencies in America
好吧，也许在你的国家不是这样，但今天我们讨论的是美国的紧急情况。
and jobs.
以及职业。
So people who can help you in an emergency.
也就是那些能在紧急情况下帮助你的人。
So before we get into those words and phrases, let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
在进入这些词汇和短语之前，我们先来听一下今天的对话。
Alright class, now that we're all dressed up, let's see what professions you chose.
好了，同学们，既然我们都打扮好了，来看看你们选了哪些职业。
I see a fireman, a police officer, a medic and a lifeguard.
我看到有消防员、警察、医护人员和救生员。
Can anyone tell me what these people have in common?
谁能告诉我这些人有什么共同点？
They save people from bad things.
他们从坏事中救人。
That's right.
没错。
Now class, if something bad happened and you had to get help, do you know what phone number
现在，同学们，如果发生了坏事，你需要寻求帮助，你知道该拨打什么电话号码吗？
you would call?
你会打什么电话？
911.
911。
Yes!
是的！
You would pick up the phone and dial 911.
你会拿起电话拨打911。
What are some emergency situations in which you would need to dial 911?
有哪些紧急情况需要你拨打911？
If my grandpa had a heart attack, if there was an accident, if a robber broke into the
如果我爷爷心脏病发作，如果发生了事故，如果强盗闯进了
house, if the fire alarm went off.
房子，如果火警响了。
I wouldn't call 911 if the fire alarm went off in my house.
如果我家火警响了，我不会打911。
The only time that ever happens is when we're having spaghetti for supper and my mom burns
那唯一发生的时候就是我们晚餐吃意大利面，我妈妈像往常一样
the garlic bread as usual.
把蒜香面包烤糊了。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have a couple of different jobs for people that are working specifically in
所以现在我们有几种不同的职业，专门从事
emergency situations.
紧急情况工作的人。
So let's take a look at those now in Language Takeaway.
那么，我们现在在“语言要点”中看看这些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright, so we have a teacher in today's dialogue who's talking to her students about
好的，今天对话中有一位老师，她在和学生们谈论
jobs.
职业。
Now obviously these students are very young and she says another word that means jobs.
显然这些学生年纪很小，她用了另一个词来表示职业。
What's the word she uses?
她用了什么词？
Professions.
职业。
That's the plural.
那是复数形式。
So profession is a job.
所以“职业”就是一份工作。
Let's say for example a lawyer is a profession.
比如说，律师是一种职业。
Or a doctor.
或者医生。
A doctor, a lawyer.
医生、律师。
So what's your profession is another way to ask what's your job.
所以“你的职业是什么”是另一种问“你的工作是什么”的方式。
Alright, so they're talking about professions and some of the kids dressed up as different
好的，所以他们谈论的是职业，有些孩子打扮成了不同的
people.
人。
So the first one was a fireman.
第一个是消防员。
A fireman.
消防员。
So you know the first word fire.
你知道第一个词是“火”。
A fireman is a person who puts out a fire.
消防员是灭火的人。
That means he uses water to stop a fire.
意思是他用水来阻止火势。
Very good.
很好。
So a fireman puts out fires.
所以消防员负责灭火。
Now apart from a fireman we also have a police officer.
除了消防员，我们还有警察。
A police officer.
警察。
So an officer is someone who works in an official capacity.
所以“警官”是指以官方身份工作的人。
So in a job.
也就是在工作中。
So we could say he is a police officer or a policeman or a policewoman.
所以我们可以说他是警察，或者男警察，或者女警察。
So three ways to say this.
所以有三种说法。
So officer is for both genders, right?
所以“警官”适用于两种性别，对吧？
A man or a woman could be a police officer.
男人或女人都可以是警察。
That's right.
没错。
So you're going to hear this very often because policeman doesn't explain a woman police officer.
所以你会经常听到这个词，因为“男警察”不能指女警察。
So we use police officer to be general.
所以我们用“警察”来泛指。
So we have a fireman, a police officer, a medic.
所以我们有消防员、警察、医护人员。
Now what is this medic?
那什么是医护人员？
A medic is a kind of doctor, someone who will look at your health or help you if you've
医护人员是一种医生，会检查你的健康或在你受伤时帮助你，
hurt yourself, who usually works on the road like driving to an accident or driving to
通常在路上工作，比如开车去事故现场或
a fire with police officers.
和警察一起开车去火灾现场。
So these people help police officers and firemen when there's an emergency.
所以这些人在紧急情况下帮助警察和消防员。
Okay.
好的。
So a medic is not really a doctor.
所以医护人员不完全是医生。
He's more of a specific person that can help you if you have maybe some cuts or bruises
他更像是一个特定的人，可以在你有一些割伤或瘀伤时帮助你，
or will help you out.
或者会帮你处理。
Right.
对。
So they will stop your bleeding or will help take you to the hospital and they'll make
所以他们会帮你止血，或者帮你送到医院，并确保
sure that you're healthy when you get to the hospital.
你到医院时是健康的。
But they are not really like a doctor where you work in a hospital or a doctor's office.
但他们不像在医院或诊所工作的医生那样。
Okay.
好的。
And our last profession is a lifeguard.
我们最后一个职业是救生员。
Well think about these two words.
嗯，想想这两个词。
We have life and we have guard.
我们有“生命”和“守卫”。
Guard is like protect.
“守卫”就像保护。
So a person that protects your life.
所以是保护你生命的人。
Hmm, interesting.
嗯，有意思。
Well this is someone who usually works at the beach or at a pool.
这个职业的人通常在海滩或游泳池工作。
They have a special chair and usually they have a cross on their bathing suit or on their
他们有一把特殊的椅子，通常泳衣或毛巾上有个十字标志，
towel and this means that they're going to help protect people who are at the beach.
这意味着他们会帮助保护在海滩上的人。
So if someone can't swim, the lifeguard will run or swim to get them and save them.
如果有人不会游泳，救生员会跑过去或游过去救他们。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So you have a lifeguard.
所以你有救生员。
Now this is for men and women as well, right?
这个职业男女都可以做，对吧？
A lifeguard.
救生员。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So interesting professions.
真是有趣的职业。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back shortly.
我们再来听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Alright class, now that we're all dressed up, let's see what professions you chose.
好了，同学们，既然我们都打扮好了，来看看你们选了哪些职业。
Ah, I see a fireman, a police officer, a medic and a lifeguard.
啊，我看到了消防员、警察、医护人员和救生员。
Can anyone tell me what these people have in common?
谁能告诉我这些人有什么共同点？
They save people from bad things.
他们从坏事中救人。
That's right.
没错。
Now class, if something bad happened and you had to get help, do you know what phone number
现在，同学们，如果发生了坏事需要求助，你们知道要打什么电话号码吗？
you would call?
911.
911。
Yes.
是的。
You would pick up the phone and dial 911.
你会拿起电话拨911。
What are some emergency situations in which you would need to dial 911?
有哪些紧急情况需要拨911？
If my grandpa had a heart attack.
如果我爷爷心脏病发作。
If there was an accident.
如果发生了事故。
If a robber broke into the house.
如果有强盗闯入房子。
If the fire alarm went off.
如果火警响了。
I wouldn't call 911 if the fire alarm went off in my house.
如果我家火警响了，我不会打911。
The only time that ever happens is when we're having spaghetti for supper and my mom burns
那唯一发生的时候是我们吃意大利面晚餐，我妈妈像往常一样把蒜香面包烤焦了。
the garlic bread as usual.
Alright, we're back so now let's start with Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了，现在开始流利度训练。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Our first item in Fluency Builder we've already talked about.
流利度训练的第一项我们已经讨论过了。
The number in America to call when you have an emergency is 911.
美国紧急情况下的电话号码是911。
So we usually say, hey, dial 911.
所以我们通常说，嘿，拨911。
Okay, so that's a verb there, to dial.
好的，所以那是一个动词，“拨号”。
Exactly.
没错。
To dial means to select the numbers for a phone call.
“拨号”意思是选择电话号码来打电话。
To telephone someone.
给某人打电话。
To telephone someone, to dial.
给某人打电话，拨号。
So you can dial 911 or dial my office number.
所以你可以拨911或拨我办公室号码。
Or I tried to dial your home number but no one answered.
或者我试着拨你家号码，但没人接。
Okay.
好的。
Now you can call 911 for many different situations or emergency.
现在你可以为很多不同情况或紧急情况打911。
One of the kids said, well, if my grandpa had a heart attack.
一个孩子说，嗯，如果我爷爷心脏病发作。
Okay, so this is an example of an emergency.
好的，所以这是一个紧急情况的例子。
A heart attack is a medical problem.
心脏病发作是一个医疗问题。
It's when your heart cannot receive oxygen.
就是你的心脏无法获得氧气。
Okay, so your heart stops beating sometimes.
好的，所以你的心脏有时会停止跳动。
That's right.
没错。
Sorry.
抱歉。
It's when your heart does not receive enough blood or oxygen.
就是你的心脏得不到足够的血液或氧气。
So it's when your heart stops beating.
所以是心脏停止跳动的时候。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So that's a heart attack.
所以那就是心脏病发作。
Now another possible emergency situation is if the fire alarm goes off.
另一个可能的紧急情况是火警响了。
This often happens in office buildings and schools.
这经常发生在办公楼和学校里。
So you hear a dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee
所以你会听到“嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀嘀”
or some kind of strange noise.
或某种奇怪的声音。
Well that's because there's maybe a fire or some smoke in your building.
那是因为你的楼里可能有火灾或烟雾。
And so usually when this sound goes off, it automatically calls the police and the fire
所以通常当这个声音响起时，它会自动呼叫警察和消防部门。
department.
Okay.
好的。
Now there's an interesting phrasal verb that is used along with this word fire alarm.
现在有一个有趣的短语动词和“火警”这个词一起使用。
We say the fire alarm goes off or the fire alarm went off.
我们说“火警响了”或“火警响过”。
So that means it started to sound, to emit a sound.
所以意思是它开始发出声音。
So the verb here, as you said it's a phrasal verb, is to go off.
所以这里的动词，如你所说，是一个短语动词，是“响起”。
We could say my alarm went off.
我们可以说我的闹钟响了。
Or every morning at 7 o'clock my alarm goes off.
或者每天早上7点我的闹钟响。
Okay, that means your alarm begins to make a sound.
好的，意思是你的闹钟开始发出声音。
A very annoying sound.
一个非常烦人的声音。
You know, it's the worst sound ever.
你知道，这是最糟糕的声音。
But a lot of things can go off.
但很多东西都可以“响”。
We could talk about a bell or an alarm.
我们可以说铃或警报响了。
Or fireworks.
或者放烟花。
Or fireworks go off.
或者烟花爆炸。
And well, the last emergency that we were talking about is if a robber broke into the
嗯，我们刚才讨论的最后一个紧急情况是，如果强盗闯进了
house.
房子。
So if a robber breaks in.
所以如果强盗闯进来。
To break into.
闯入。
This means to enter, to go inside without permission or without a key.
这意味着未经许可或没有钥匙就进入、进去。
Illegally.
非法地。
So you don't have to break something but usually you break a window or a door.
所以你不一定要打破东西，但通常你会打破窗户或门。
But this means that someone comes into your house looking to steal something.
但这意味着有人进入你的房子想偷东西。
So usually you have to use force.
所以通常你得使用暴力。
For example, if I forget my keys inside my car and I have to break into my own car, that
比如，如果我把钥匙忘在车里，不得不闯入自己的车，那
means maybe I have to force the door open or maybe break the window.
意味着我可能得强行打开门或打破窗户。
Yeah, it's not fun.
是啊，这可不有趣。
I think it usually ends up being very expensive.
我觉得通常结果会很贵。
Yes, it does.
是的，确实如此。
Alright, so those are all the phrases we have for today.
好了，这就是我们今天所有的短语。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the very last time.
我们最后再听一遍对话吧。
Alright class, now that we're all dressed up, let's see what professions you chose.
好了，同学们，既然我们都打扮好了，来看看你们选了哪些职业。
Ah, I see a fireman, a police officer, a medic and a lifeguard.
啊，我看到一个消防员、一个警察、一个医护人员和一个救生员。
Can anyone tell me what these people have in common?
谁能告诉我这些人有什么共同点？
They save people from bad things.
他们从坏事中救人。
That's right.
没错。
Now class, if something bad happened and you had to get help, do you know what phone number
现在，同学们，如果发生了坏事，你需要求助，你们知道该打什么电话号码
you would call?
吗？
911.
911。
Yes.
是的。
You would pick up the phone and dial 911.
你会拿起电话拨911。
What are some emergency situations in which you would need to dial 911?
有哪些紧急情况需要你拨打911？
If my grandpa had a heart attack.
如果我爷爷心脏病发作。
If there was an accident.
如果发生了事故。
If a robber broke into the house.
如果强盗闯进了房子。
If the fire alarm went off.
如果火警响了。
I wouldn't call 911 if the fire alarm went off in my house.
如果我家火警响了，我不会打911。
The only time that ever happens is when we're having spaghetti for supper and my mom burns
唯一发生这种情况的时候是我们吃意大利面晚餐，我妈妈像往常一样
the garlic bread as usual.
把蒜香面包烤焦了。
So Marco, when you were a kid and your teacher said, what jobs are there, what professions
那么Marco，你小时候老师问，有哪些工作，有哪些
are there, what profession would you like, what did you answer?
职业，你想要什么职业，你是怎么回答的？
I always wanted to be a pilot.
我一直想当飞行员。
Oh, pilot.
哦，飞行员。
So you wanted to fly airplanes.
所以你想开飞机。
Yeah, I wanted to be a jet pilot.
是啊，我想当喷气机飞行员。
Actually I collected books about it, I read up about it, so even till now I probably still
实际上我收集了关于它的书，我读过很多，所以直到现在可能还
remember like the capacity of certain jets or what types of weapons they have.
记得某些喷气机的容量或它们有什么武器。
I was really, really into it.
我当时真的很着迷。
Wow, I never knew this about you.
哇，我从来不知道你还有这一面。
Yeah, what about you?
是啊，你呢？
I could never decide as a kid.
我小时候一直拿不定主意。
I remember we had to draw pictures of what I will look like in 20 years and everyone
我记得我们得画20年后自己会是什么样子，每个人
had these pictures, I will be a doctor, I'll be a veterinarian, I'll be the president.
都画了这些图，我会是医生、兽医、总统。
I never knew what to draw, so I think I copied my friend, she wanted to be a lawyer.
我从来不知道画什么，所以我想我抄了我朋友的，她想当律师。
I was like, okay, that sounds okay.
我就想，好吧，听起来还行。
Yeah, I think it's hard and usually what you want to be as a kid, you don't do it when
是啊，我觉得这很难，而且通常你小时候想当的，长大后
you're older.
并不会去做。
Yeah, it's because of my vision, I didn't have 20-20 vision to actually join the Air
是啊，因为我的视力，我没有20/20的视力，所以没法加入空
Force.
军。
Well, and a lot of kids don't know how many jobs there are out there.
嗯，而且很多孩子不知道外面有多少工作。
You know the big ones, doctor, lawyer, fireman, policeman, astronaut.
你知道那些大的，医生、律师、消防员、警察、宇航员。
So I guess the question for you is what's your profession?
所以我想问你的问题是，你的职业是什么？
Tell us about it, especially if it's one of the less famous professions out there, because
跟我们说说吧，特别是如果它是那些不太知名的职业之一，因为
there's a lot that I don't know about those.
有很多我都不了解。
Our website is EnglishPod.com, we hope to see you there and until next time.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com，希望在那里见到你，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。